<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>BawaDev</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on BawaDev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bawadev.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Beginner's Guide to Secure Communication in Web Development (SSL/TLS)</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/java-security-part-https/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/java-security-part-https/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s digital landscape, secure communication is essential for building safe, reliable web applications. As a beginner developer, understanding the concepts of encryption, HTTPS, Keystore,Trustore, Mutual TLS (mTLS), and secure configurations in Spring Boot is crucial. This guide provides an overview of these topics, complete with explanations and examples..</description></item><item><title>Evolution and developing stages in field of psychology</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/psyco-3-evalu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/psyco-3-evalu/</guid><description>Hey there, fellow psychology enthusiasts! Let&amp;rsquo;s take a stroll through the colorful landscape of psychology, where every twist and turn reveals a new facet of the human mind and behavior. From the foundational concepts of Structuralism to the cutting-edge frontiers of Health Psychology, buckle up for a wild ride through the evolution of psychological thought.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Defense Mechanisms</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/psyco-1-def-mech/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/psyco-1-def-mech/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered why sometimes you or people around you act in certain ways that just don’t seem to make sense? Well, welcome to the fascinating world of defense mechanisms! These are like your mind&amp;rsquo;s secret agents, working behind the scenes to protect you from stuff that might be too uncomfortable to handle head-on.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Motivation</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/psyco-2-motiv/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/psyco-2-motiv/</guid><description>Motivation is the spark that ignites action, the force that propels individuals towards their goals. Embedded within the intricate web of human psychology, motivation dictates the direction, intensity, and persistence of our behaviors. In this article, we embark on a journey through the labyrinth of motivation theories, unraveling the essence of what moves us.</description></item><item><title>Demystifying IOC Containers: A Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/java-spring-ioc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/java-spring-ioc/</guid><description>In the realm of software development, there exists a concept that often perplexes beginners: Inversion of Control (IOC) containers. While the term may sound daunting, understanding IOC containers is pivotal for mastering modern software architecture. In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll unravel the mysteries surrounding IOC containers, elucidating their significance and benefits for beginners.</description></item><item><title>Spring Beans: A Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/java-spring-beans/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/java-spring-beans/</guid><description>As the chilly grip of winter loosens its hold, nature awakens from its slumber, and so does the world of software development with the arrival of Spring. No, we&amp;rsquo;re not talking about the season of blossoms and new beginnings, but rather about Spring Framework – a versatile and powerful framework for building robust Java applications.</description></item><item><title>Java Lambda: All you need to know to code</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/java-lambda-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/java-lambda-1/</guid><description>Java lambdas provide a concise way to express instances of single-method interfaces (functional interfaces). They enhance code readability and maintainability by allowing you to write more compact and expressive code for functional programming constructs. Lambdas also facilitate the use of functional interfaces in the Java API, making it easier to work with collections and streams. Overall, they contribute to more efficient and modern Java programming practices.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://bawadev.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/about/</guid><description>About Author Pasindu Munasinghe is a highly skilled software engineer and a consultant with expertise in multiple areas of software development. Holding a Bachelor of Science in Information Technology with honors from University of Moratuwa and currently he is reading for a Higher Diploma in psychology and counseling in IMBS campus,Sri Lanka. Pasindu has cultivated his skills in backend development, database management, and frontend development. His enthusiasm for technology propels him to continually learn and tackle new challenges.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://bawadev.github.io/gallery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/gallery/</guid><description>Kylie the highend store This website is created using React js. It is best suited for retail perposes Kylie Store home page
Product Detail page</description></item><item><title/><link>https://bawadev.github.io/search/placeholder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/search/placeholder/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Posts Archive</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/archive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/archive/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>