<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DEVELOPMENTS on BawaDev</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/tags/developments/</link><description>Recent content in DEVELOPMENTS on BawaDev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bawadev.github.io/tags/developments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Beginner's Guide to Secure Communication in Web Development (SSL/TLS)</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/dev-java-security-part-https/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/dev-java-security-part-https/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s digital landscape, secure communication is essential for building safe, reliable web applications. As a beginner developer, understanding the concepts of encryption, HTTPS, Keystore,Trustore, Mutual TLS (mTLS), and secure configurations in Spring Boot is crucial. This guide provides an overview of these topics, complete with explanations and examples..</description></item><item><title>Demystifying IOC Containers: A Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/dev-java-spring-ioc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/dev-java-spring-ioc/</guid><description>In the realm of software development, there exists a concept that often perplexes beginners: Inversion of Control (IOC) containers. While the term may sound daunting, understanding IOC containers is pivotal for mastering modern software architecture. In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll unravel the mysteries surrounding IOC containers, elucidating their significance and benefits for beginners.</description></item><item><title>Spring Beans: A Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/dev-java-spring-beans/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/dev-java-spring-beans/</guid><description>As the chilly grip of winter loosens its hold, nature awakens from its slumber, and so does the world of software development with the arrival of Spring. No, we&amp;rsquo;re not talking about the season of blossoms and new beginnings, but rather about Spring Framework – a versatile and powerful framework for building robust Java applications.</description></item></channel></rss>