<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on BawaDev</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on BawaDev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bawadev.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Beginner's Guide to Secure Communication in Web Development (SSL/TLS)</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/2024-04-21-java-security-part-https/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/2024-04-21-java-security-part-https/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s digital landscape, secure communication is essential for building safe, reliable web applications. As a beginner developer, understanding the concepts of encryption, HTTPS, Keystore,Trustore, Mutual TLS (mTLS), and secure configurations in Spring Boot is crucial. This guide provides an overview of these topics, complete with explanations and examples..</description></item><item><title>Understanding Defense Mechanisms</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/psyco-1-def-mech/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/psyco-1-def-mech/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered why sometimes you or people around you act in certain ways that just don’t seem to make sense? Well, welcome to the fascinating world of defense mechanisms! These are like your mind&amp;rsquo;s secret agents, working behind the scenes to protect you from stuff that might be too uncomfortable to handle head-on.</description></item><item><title>Demystifying IOC Containers: A Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/2024-03-16-java-spring-ioc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/2024-03-16-java-spring-ioc/</guid><description>In the realm of software development, there exists a concept that often perplexes beginners: Inversion of Control (IOC) containers. While the term may sound daunting, understanding IOC containers is pivotal for mastering modern software architecture. In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll unravel the mysteries surrounding IOC containers, elucidating their significance and benefits for beginners.
Understanding IOC Containers At its core, Inversion of Control (IOC) is a design principle aimed at decoupling dependencies within a software system.</description></item><item><title>Exploring the Blooming World of Spring Beans: A Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/2024-01-16-java-spring-beans/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/2024-01-16-java-spring-beans/</guid><description>Exploring the Blooming World of Spring Beans: A Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide As the chilly grip of winter loosens its hold, nature awakens from its slumber, and so does the world of software development with the arrival of Spring. No, we&amp;rsquo;re not talking about the season of blossoms and new beginnings, but rather about Spring Framework – a versatile and powerful framework for building robust Java applications.
At the heart of the Spring Framework lies a fundamental concept: beans.</description></item><item><title>Java Lambda: All you need to know to code</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/2024-01-09-java-lambda-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/2024-01-09-java-lambda-1/</guid><description>Java lambdas provide a concise way to express instances of single-method interfaces (functional interfaces). They enhance code readability and maintainability by allowing you to write more compact and expressive code for functional programming constructs. Lambdas also facilitate the use of functional interfaces in the Java API, making it easier to work with collections and streams. Overall, they contribute to more efficient and modern Java programming practices.</description></item></channel></rss>