<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Middleware on BawaDev</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/tags/middleware/</link><description>Recent content in Middleware on BawaDev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bawadev.github.io/tags/middleware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Integrating a React Application with a Backend API Using Redux Toolkit</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/dev-react-redux-fetch-api-data-template/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/dev-react-redux-fetch-api-data-template/</guid><description>This is a detailed article on integrating a React application with a backend API using Redux Toolkit and custom hooks. In this article we will give you a easy to follow template to integrate your react front end with a REST backend. This step-by-step guide will help developers set up their applications to fetch data from a backend server and manage it efficiently using Redux Toolkit.</description></item><item><title>Mastering Redux Middleware</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/dev-react-redux-middleware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/dev-react-redux-middleware/</guid><description>Redux middleware is a powerful feature that allows you to extend the capabilities of Redux. Middleware sits between the dispatching of an action and the moment it reaches the reducer, enabling you to intercept and act upon actions, perform asynchronous operations, and implement various cross-cutting concerns such as logging, crash reporting, and more.</description></item><item><title>React js Backend Integration</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/dev-react-redux-fetch-api-data/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/dev-react-redux-fetch-api-data/</guid><description>Connecting a React front end with REST backends and managing state with Redux Toolkit can initially seem daunting, but with a structured approach, you can handle it efficiently. Here’s a step-by-step guide for beginners:</description></item></channel></rss>