<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PSYCHOLOGY on BawaDev</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/tags/psychology/</link><description>Recent content in PSYCHOLOGY on BawaDev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bawadev.github.io/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Evelution and develping stages of field of psycology</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/psyco-3-evalu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/psyco-3-evalu/</guid><description>Hey there, fellow psychology enthusiasts! Let&amp;rsquo;s take a stroll through the colorful landscape of psychology, where every twist and turn reveals a new facet of the human mind and behavior. From the foundational concepts of Structuralism to the cutting-edge frontiers of Health Psychology, buckle up for a wild ride through the evolution of psychological thought.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Defense Mechanisms</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/psyco-1-def-mech/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/psyco-1-def-mech/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered why sometimes you or people around you act in certain ways that just don’t seem to make sense? Well, welcome to the fascinating world of defense mechanisms! These are like your mind&amp;rsquo;s secret agents, working behind the scenes to protect you from stuff that might be too uncomfortable to handle head-on.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Motivation</title><link>https://bawadev.github.io/post/psyco-2-motiv/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bawadev.github.io/post/psyco-2-motiv/</guid><description>Motivation is the spark that ignites action, the force that propels individuals towards their goals. Embedded within the intricate web of human psychology, motivation dictates the direction, intensity, and persistence of our behaviors. In this article, we embark on a journey through the labyrinth of motivation theories, unraveling the essence of what moves us.</description></item></channel></rss>